Guide to the Western Americana Card Photograph File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Identified Photographers, circa 1851-1965; Series I; 672
  - Hiestand, Joseph G. (born 1862)
    - First passenger train on summit of Pike's Peak, Colorado, circa 1890; 11.0 x 18.4 cm on mount 12.2 x 20.0 cm (Box 7)
    - Cathedral Spires, Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1895; 18.4 x 11.2 cm on mount 20.2 x 12.7 cm (Box 7)
      Image Number 12
    - View of Manitou Springs, Colorado, circa 1895; 11.2 x 18.2 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 7)
  - Hillers, John K. (1843-1925), attributed
    Hillers was originally hired as a boatman for a geographical survey expedition led by John Wesley Powell in 1871 and became the expedition's photographer in 1872. Over the next twenty years he created exploration and ethnographic photographs for the United States government
    - Studio portrait of Domingo, a Mescalero Apache Indian man, 1879-1881; 16.3 x 10.9 cm on mount 16.8 x 11.2 cm (Box 7)
  - Hilliard
    Photographer in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
    - Tal-A-Mas-Mico, or King of the Forest, Christened, John D. Bemo (circa 1825-90), circa 1874; 8.8 x 5.9 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.3 cm (Box 7)
  - Hirschfeld, Alfred Cyril
    Photographer in Dyea, Alaska
    - Lake Lindeman, Alaska, circa 1896-1897; 11.9 x 17.0 cm on mount 14.0 x 21.6 cm (Box 7)
      Manuscript initials on recto: "C. R. F."
  - Hoard & Tenney
    Photography studio in Winona, Minnesota; partnership of E. Harry Hoard and Charles A. Tenney (1847-1917)
    - Ojibway (sic) Indian Chief on horseback, Leech Lake Reservation, Minnesota, circa 1875; 11.7 x 9.5 cm on mount 13.9 x 10.8 cm (Box 7)
    - Exterior portrait of Oge-mak-oche-may-osh, White Earth Chippewa Indian, White Earth, Minnesota, circa 1875; 11.8 x 9.7 cm on mount 13.9 x 10.9 cm (Box 7)
    - Church of Saint Columba, White Earth, Minnesota, circa 1875; 5.6 x 9.8 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.2 cm (Box 7)
  - Hogg, E. A., attributed
    - Blockade of wagons on Front Street, Nome, Alaska, 1900 Jul 1; 14.9 x 19.8 cm on mount 17.5 x 22.6 cm (Box 7)
      On the verso of a cardboard mount for the Nowell Studio, operated by Frank H. Nowell in Nome, Alaska, Seattle, Washington
  - Holme, James S.
    - St. James Methodist Church, Central City, Colorado, 1948; 16.6 x 11.9 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
  - Houseworth, Thomas (1829-1915)
    - El Capitan, 3,300 Feet High, Yosemite Valley, California, circa 1874-1886; 21.6 x 16.1 cm on mount 25.1 x 20.2 cm (Box 7)
    - Grand Court, Palace Hotel, San Francisco, California, circa 1875-1886; 14.9 x 10.4 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.7 cm (Box 7)
    - Studio portrait of Hattie Moore, 1881 Apr; 7.7 x 5.7 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 7)
      Letterpress caption on recto: "The Compliments of Miss Hattie Moore, to the Lady Patrons of the Tivoli Garden, on the occasion of her Five Hundredth Consecutive Appearance in Opera, Saturday Evening, April 2d, 1881, as Olivette"
    - California's 40th birthday, Grant Avenue, San Francisco, California, 1890 Sep 9; 11.9 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.6 cm (Box 7)
      View of a parade in San Francisco
  - Howard, Charles (born circa 1842)
    Soldier and photographer for the Stanton Expedition in 1877, traveling throughout eastern Wyoming, western Nebraska and into the Black Hills of Dakota Territory
    - View of Fort Laramie, Wyoming, 1877; 20.3 x 28.1 cm on a trimmed mount 21.9 x 29.2 cm (Box 7)
      Gift of Michael Vinson, 2012
      Pencil inscriotion on verso misidentifies the image as Fort Phil Kearny
  - Howell, Bert
    Photographer in Osage City, Kansas
    - Two women, identified as Anna Crane and May Adams, posing with two bicycles in front of a house, 1895 August; 9.9 x 13.9 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.4 cm (Box 7)
  - Howland, Benjamin Franklin (1828-1900)
    - Studio portrait of A. H. H. Stuart, circa 1880; 16.1 x 10.5 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.9 cm (Box 7)
      Signed "Very sincerely, your friend"
  - Huey & Laws
    Photography studio in Nome, Alaska; partnership of Harry H. Huey and H. W. Laws
    - Washday in Eskimoville, circa 1900-1906; 16.3 x 21.5 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
    - Yukon native and bride, circa 1906-1908; 15.2 x 20.2 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
    - Eskimo with king salmon, circa 1906-1908; 21.5 x 16.3 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
  - Huffman, Laton Alton (1854-1931)
    Photographer in Milestown (later known as Miles City), Montana and Wallace, Idaho
    - Gerk-line (sic) twelve on the old freight road, 1883; 22.6 x 27.9 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
      Wagon train on a mountain road
    - Studio portrait of Cheyenne Chief Two Moons, 1913; 27.9 x 23.4 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
      Manuscript inscription on verso states that Two Moons "led the Sioux Indians at the Little Big Horn"
  - Hull, Arundel C.
    Photographer in Fremont, Nebraska
    - Studio portrait of an elderly American Indian, circa 1870; 5.8 x 6.7 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.0 cm (Box 7)
  - Hunt, Phinney S. (1866-1917)
    Photographer in Valdez, Alaska
    - Dr. E. Fahrig with assistants leaving Valdez for Nugget Creek, Alaska, 1907 Jul 22; 14.7 x 19.9 cm on mount 20.4 x 25.5 cm (Box 7)
  - Jackson, Albert L.
    - Studio portrait of a Japanese man posed kneeling and wearing a kimono, circa 1895; 14.5 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.4 x 11.8 cm (Box 7)
  - Jackson Brothers
    Photography studio in Omaha, Nebraska; partnership of William Henry Jackson (1843-1942) and Edward Jackson
    - Studio portrait of a woman and man, circa 1867-1870; 9.4 x 5.6 cm on mount 6.2 x 10 cm (Box 7)
  - Jackson, William Henry (1843-1942)
    Jackson was an explorer, painter, and photographer known for his images of the American West in Jackson had a successful commercial career that began in Denver, and included operations in San Francisco, California, and Washington, District of Columbia
    - Eroded sandstones, Monument Valley Park, Colorado, circa 1875; 18.8 x 11.9 cm on mount 20.4 x 12.6 cm (Box 7)
    - Red sandstones near Platte Canyon in Roxborough State Park, Colorado, circa 1879-1882; 10.6 x 16.6 cm on mount 11.5 x 17.7 cm (Box 7)
    - Georgetown, Colorado, from the east, circa 1880-1890; 10.8 x 18.4 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
      Purchased from Michael Vinson on the Chandler White and Philena Pennell Smith Acquisitions Fund, 2013
      Image number 1810
    - Royal Gorge, Grand Canyon of the Arkansas River, Colorado, circa 1881-1890; 16.7 x 10.4 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.4 cm (Box 7)
      Stamped description on the verso
    - Ute Medicine Column, Monument Valley Park, Colorado, circa 1881-1890; 17.8 x 11.2 cm on mount 20.4 x 12.6 cm (Box 7)
    - Monument Valley Park, Colorado, circa 1881-1890; 16.7 x 10.4 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.4 cm (Box 7)
    - Tunnel No. 9, Elevenmile Canyon, Colorado, Colorado Midlands Railroad, circa 1881-1890; 10.7 x 16.7 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.7 cm (Box 7)
    - Sandstone tower, Monument Valley Park, circa 1881-1890; 18.0 x 12.0 cm on mount 20.4 x 12.6 cm (Box 7)
    - Seven Falls, also known as Cheyenne Falls, on South Cheyenne Creek, South Cheyenne Canyon, El Paso County, Colorado, circa 1882-1885; 18.5 x 10.8 cm on mount 20.2 x 12.6 cm (Box 7)
      Gift of Mary Jessup, 2010
    - Salida, Colorado, circa 1882-1889; 10.0 x 16.6 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 7)
    - View of Idaho Springs, Clear Creek County, Colorado, circa 1882-1900; 10.8 x 18.3 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
      Image number 1807
    - Hanging rock, Clear Creek Canyon, Colorado, circa 1890-1900; 16.7 x 10.6 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.5 cm (Box 7)
    - Head of a big horn sheep, circa 1890-1900; 16.6 x 10.6 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.4 cm (Box 7)
    - Pike's Peak from the Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1890-1900; 10.7 x 16.7 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.6 cm (Box 7)
    - Pike's Peak from the Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1890-1900; 10.7 x 16.7 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.6 cm (Box 7)
    - Poncha Springs and Pass, Colorado, circa 1890-1900; 10.1 x 17.1 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 7)
    - Mother Grundy, Clear Creek Canyon, Colorado, circa 1890-1900; 16.6 x 10.5 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.5 cm (Box 7)
      Rock outcropping above railroad tracks
    - Sierra Blanca from Fort Garland, Colorado, circa 1880; 15.0 x 16.6 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 7)
    - East from Iron Springs Station, near Manitou Springs, Colorado, Midlands Railroad, circa 1886-1900; 11.0 x 18.1 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 7)
    - View of Aboursville (later known as Arbour-villa and Conrow, near Poncha Springs), Colorado, circa 1880-1886; 10.4 x 16.6 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.3 cm (Box 7)
    - View of an adobe brick arcade at Mission San Juan Capistrano in San Juan Capistrano, California, circa 1880-1890; 18.6 x 11.3 cm on mount 21.7 x 13.4 cm (Box 7)
    - South Platte River near Idylwilde, Colorado, along the Colorado Midland Railway, circa 1881-1888; 10.8 x 18.3 cm, unmounted (Box 7)
    - View of Royal Gorge, Colorado, from the bridge. Denver & Rio Grande Railway tracks wind through the Royal Gorge beside the Arkansas River, Colorado, circa 1882-1900; 18.6 x 11.3 cm on mount 21.7 x 13.3 cm (Box 7)
    - Manitou Springs, Colorado, circa 1885-1895; 10.6 x 16.7 cm on mount 13.6 x 21.4 cm (Box 7)
  - Jacobs, William L. (born 1854)
    Photographer in Oakland, Nebraska
    - Overview on Oakland Avenue in Oakland, Nebraska from the steeple of the Methodist Episcopal Church, circa 1895; 9.9 x 14.3 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.6 cm (Box 8)
  - James, Eli E. (born 1857)
    Photographer in Yakima, Washington
    - Residence of Alexander Miller, circa 1900; 18.2 x 24.2 cm on mount 23.5 x 25.1 cm (Box 8)
  - James, William E.
    Photographer in Brooklyn, New York
    - Studio portrait of John Allen Hosmer (1850-1907), 1866; 9.4 x 5.8 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.5 cm (Box 8)
      Author of A Trip to the States by the Way of the Yellowstone and Missouri (1867)
  - Jarvis Studios
    Photography studio in Pasadena, California
    - Jack Rabbit Drive, 2,500 killed, 1888 Dec 17; 11.2 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 8)
  - Jean DuBois Company
    Photography studio in Denver, Colorado; a company owned by Jean "Jack" DuBois, a motion picture camera operator in Denver, circa 1930-1950
    - Young girl's face painted on boards, circa 1940; 17.3 x 12.1 cm, unmounted (Box 8)
  - Jesse, Maxmilian T.
    Photographer in Texas
    - Studio portrait of a man and woman, circa 1867-1882; 9.9 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.6 x 6.3 cm (Box 8)
  - Johnson Studio
    Photography studio in San Francisco, California
    - Studio portrait of a boy to commemorate his first communion, circa 1920-1930; 19.0 x 12.7 cm in folder 25.4 x 17.6 cm (Box 8)
  - Johnson, F. Elmer
    - Studio portrait of Professor J. "The Greek" Loris brandishing a pistol, circa 1890-1900; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.3 x 10.7 cm (Box 8)
  - Johnson, Lute H.
    - Green River with butte in the distance, Wyoming, 1905; 9.0 x 11.5 cm, unmounted (Box 8)
    - Ferry crossing the Green River near Jensen, Utah, 1905 Aug; 10.2 x 12.9 cm, unmounted (Box 8)
  - Johnston, John S.
    - William Frederick "Buffalo Bill" Cody (1846-1917) on horseback, circa 1894; 16.8 x 22.3 cm on mount 17.7 x 22.7 cm (Box 8)
  - Johnston, William
    Photographer in Colborne, Ontario
    - Studio portrait of John Sunday (circa 1795-1875), also known as Shawundais, a Missisauga Indian chief and a Methodist minister, circa 1870; 9 x 5.8 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 8)
      Gift of Peter Sindell, 2011
  - Judkins, David Roby (1836-1909)
    - Studio portrait of Bailey Gazert, Henry L. Yesler, and Moses R. Maddocks, 1886; 6.2 x 9.2 cm on mount 8.8 x 9.4 cm (Box 8)
  - Kaadt, Christian G. (1868-1905)
    Photographer in Santa Fe, New Mexico
    - View of 215 East De Vargas Street, Santa Fe, New Mexico, circa 1906; 8.1 x 10.7 cm, unmounted (Box 8)
      Identified as the oldest house in the United States built by a Europeans, built circa 1646
  - Kenney, Bartlett F.
    - Studio portrait of Washakie (circa 1804-1900), Chief of the Shoshone Indians, circa 1890; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.7 x 11.0 cm (Box 8)
  - Klindt, Charles
    - Mission Valley from Cable Pavilion, San Diego, California, 1894; 11.2 x 18.0 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 8)
    - Residence of Ulysses S. Grant, Jr., in San Diego, California, circa 1894; 11.4 x 17.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 8)
  - Knight, M. W.
    Photographer in Bowie, Texas
    - Railroad depot in Bowie, Texas for the Chicago, Rock Island & Central Railway with seven men on the platform, circa 1890-1900; 15.3 x 20.6 cm on mount 20.2 x 25.4 cm (Box 8)
    - Railway depot in Bowie, Texas for the Fort Worth and Denver City Railway, circa 1890-1900; 15.4 x 20.6 cm on mount 20.3 x 25.5 cm (Box 8)
  - Kopke
    Photographer in Brooklyn, New York; John F. Kopke (born 1859) or his son, Henry Kopke (born 1873)
    - Studio portrait of Charles E. Gensch, a sharpshooter, with a target pasted on the image of a divan in the portrait, circa 1895; 14.2 x 9.6 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 8)
  - Kopp & Potter
    Photography studio in Livingston, Montana
    - Engineers Headquarters, National Park Branch, Livingston, Montana, circa 1883 Jul; 9.0 x 16.1 cm on mount 10 x 17.9 cm (Box 8)
      Image includes Joel Barber Clough (1823-1887), division engineer in charge of construction for the Northern Pacific Railroad Company line in Yellowstone National Park, and Arthur Brown artist in oil, from Newcastle-upon-Tyne and London, England. Identified in pencil on verso
  - La Roche, Frank (1853-1934)
    - Studio portrait of Kikisoblu (circa 1820-1896), also known as Wewick or Princess Angeline, eldest daughter of Chief Seattle (chief of the Suquamish and Duwamish Indians), circa 1893; 13.7 x 9.7 cm, unmounted (Box 8)
      Accompanied by a printed card with a brief biographical sketch of Angeline
  - Laughlin, Kyle E.
    Photographer in Moscow, Idaho
    - Site of the Lapwai Mission, Spalding, Idaho, circa 1954; 25.3 x 20.3 cm on mount 25.3 x 20.3 cm (Box 8)
      Typescript of a letter by the photographer accompanies describing the photographic print and the context for its donation
  - Lawrence & Houseworth
    Photography studio in San Francisco, California; partnership of optician George S. Lawrence and Thomas Houseworth
    - Pioneer Woolen Mills, Black Point, San Francisco, California, 1864-1866; 5.8 x 9.4 cm on mount 6.1 x 10.1 cm (Box 8)
  - Lawrence, W. H., & Company
    Photography studio in Denver, Colorado
    - Copy photograph of a painting of Marshall Pass, Colorado and mountain landscape in 1885 by James M. Bagley (1837-1910), 1890-1892; 10.8 x 14.9 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.7 cm (Box 8)
    - Black Canyon, Colorado and the Denver and Rio Grande Railroad, 1890-1892; 11.4 x 19.2 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.2 cm (Box 8)
  - Lenny & Sawyers
    Photography studio of William J. Lenny and William A. Sawyer in Purcell, Oklahoma
    - Kiowa beef issue; view of a group of Kiowa Indian woman butchering a steer, as well as other Kiowa Indians, circa 1890; 11.3 x 18.6 cm on mount 13.4 x 21.6 cm (Box 8)
      Purchased from Barney Chapman on the Walter McClintock Memorial Fund, 2010
  - Lenthall, Henry (flourished 1862-1878)
    Photographer in London, England
    - Studio portrait of Henry Rickard, head and shoulders, circa 1862-1878; 9.0 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.3 x 6.3 cm (Box 8)
    - Studio portrait of Henry Rickard, standing, circa 1862-1878; 9.0 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.3 x 6.3 cm (Box 8)
  - Lewis & Gibson
    Photography studio in Ann Arbor, Michigan; partnership of Jefferson Gibson (born 1851) and E. B. Lewis
    - Studio portrait of Val A. Milroy, the first postmaster of Olympia, Washington, 1883-1885; 15.3 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.6 cm (Box 8)
  - Lippincott, Joseph Barlow (1864-1942)
    Photographer in Los Angeles, California
    - San Carlos (Coolidge) Dam site, Gila River, Arizona, looking downstream, 1898-1899; 15.1 x 20.1 cm on paper mount 18.6 x 21.8 cm (Box 8)
      Probably created by Lippincott or another photographer for the United States Geological Survey
  - Loomis, Fred A. (born 1860)
    Photographer in Emporia, Kansas
    - Jewelry shop interior, probably in Emporia, Kansas, circa 1901; Oval 13.6 x 19.5 cm on mount 22.9 x 28.0 cm (Box 8)
  - Loranson, Jonas
    Photographer in Biwabik, Minnesota
    - Mine in Mesaba Quarry, Minnesota, 1892-1893; 11.7 x 19.5 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 8)
    - Hale Mine in Biwabik, Minnesota, 1893 Oct; 11.5 x 19.1 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 8)
    - Biwabik mine in Biwabik, Minnesota, 1893 Oct; 15.5 x 20.8 cm on mount 20.3 x 25.4 cm (Box 8)
  - Luke, Willington O.
    Photographer in Aztec, New Mexico
    - Exterior portrait of a shackled Navajo Indian, identified as Nesh-Kai-Hay, detained for the murder of L. S. Welsh, a trader and employee of Henry Hill at Fruitland, New Mexico, 1893 May; 14.0 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.3 x 10.5 cm (Box 8)
      Accompanied by a manuscript recounting the murder of Welsh and the capture of Nish-Kai-Hay
  - MacDougal, Daniel Trembly (1865-1958)
    Photographer in Tucson, Arizona; MacDougal was a director of the Carnegie Desert Laboratory at Tucson, Arizona
    - A Cupoca Indian in front of a house made of mesquite, arrow-weed and willow, circa 1905-1906; 12.2 x 19.7 cm, unmounted (Box 8)
  - Macurdy, James C. (born 1836)
    - West Fifth Street, Leadville, Colorado, 1880 Dec 5; 10.9 x 17.1 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.6 cm (Box 8)
      Printed and manuscript inscription on verso: "J. C. Macurdy's Views of Leadville and Scenes along the Denver & Rio Grande R. R., No. 1 for Fog Woodworth, Dec. 5th, 1880. From the Rocky Mountain Art Gallery, 103 East Fifth Street, Leadville, Colorado
  - Marks, Harvey R. (1821-1902)
    - Studio portrait of Xavier Blanchard Debray (1819-1895) wearing a military uniform of the Confederate States of America, circa 1862-1864; 9.9 x 5.8 cm on mount 10.6 x 6.3 cm (Box 8)
  - Martin, Alexander (died 1929)
    - Devil's Gate High Bridge on the Georgetown Loop, Georgetown, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 11.0 x 18.9 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 8)
      Stamped on verso: "Barkalow Bros. Denver, Colo., R.R. News Agents"
    - Balancing Rock, Manitou, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 18.7 x 10.8 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 8)
      Image number 1400
    - Gateway to Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 10.4 x 15.9 cm on mount 13.9 x 19 cm (Box 8)
      Image number 1410
    - Town and mines of Silver Plume, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 2 photographic prints, 10.5 x 15.8 cm on mount 13.8 x 18.8 cm (Box 8)
    - Georgetown, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 10.6 x 15.7 cm on mount 10.9 x 17.7 cm (Box 8)
    - Bridge above Georgetown, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 10.5 x 16.0 cm on mount 13.8 x 18.8 cm (Box 8)
      Manuscript inscription on the recto: "Bridge above Georgetown, Colorado"
    - Town and mines of Silver Plume, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 10.5 x 15.8 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 8)
    - Idaho Springs, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 10.7 x 15.8 cm on mount 13.8 x 18.8 cm (Box 8)
    - Idaho Springs, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 10.5 x 15.8 cm on mount 11.4 x 17.8 cm (Box 8)
    - Town and mines of Silver Plume, Colorado, circa 1884-1888; 10.8 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 8)
    - Copy photograph of a painting of the Georgetown Loop, Georgetown, Colorado, Colorado Central Railroad, circa 1884-1888; 18.6 x 10.9 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 8)
    - Lawrence Street, North from 16th Street, Denver, Colorado, 1888-1901; 10.5 x 15.7 cm on mount 17.7 x 11.5 cm (Box 8)
    - Idaho Springs, Colorado, circa 1890-1898; 10.9 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.4 cm (Box 8)
  - Martin, Edward (died 1882)
    - Studio portrait of Francis Noyes and an infant, circa 1867-1872; 8.6 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 8)
  - Mathers, Charles Wesley (1868-1950)
    - Men with flatboats on a river, probably the North Saskatchewan River, Saskatchewan, 1892-1904; 10.0 x 13.9 cm on mount 14.1 x 18.1 cm (Box 8)
    - Horses among tipis, 1892-1904; 7.3 x 13.2 cm oval on mount 11.0 x 17.8 cm (Box 8)
  - McBride, C. C.
    Photographer in Crawford, Nebraska
    - Red Cloud Buttes at Fort Robinson, Nebraska, on the Burlington and Missouri River Railroad, with tipis and tents in the foreground, circa 1870; 17.9 x 23.2 cm on mount 20.4 x 25.5 cm (Box 8)
    - Scene in Spearfish Canyon on the Burlington and Missouri River Railroad, circa 1870; 18.0 x 22.8 cm on mount 20.3 x 25.3 cm (Box 8)
      Advertisement on verso for the "Burlington Route"
  - McClure, Louis Charles, 1867-1957
    - Greek Theater and Colonnade of Civic Benefactors, Denver, Colorado, 1919; 19.3 x 24.2 cm, unmounted (Box 9)
  - McDonald, A. J. (born 1840)
    - Maze at Hotel Del Monte, Monterey, California, 1887-1892; 11.2 x 18.8 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
      Manuscript inscription on the verso recounts getting lost in the maze
  - McInnis, Hector C.
    Photographer in Sprague, Washington
    - Studio portrait of George Fritz Benninghoff (1851-1926), 1887; 19.0 x 12.8 cm on mount 21.5 x 13.3 cm (Box 9)
    - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of George Fritz Benninghoff (1851-1926) and his sister, Julia M. Benninghoff (born 1861) and their parents, George Benninghoff and Annie Maria Roth Benninghoff, circa 1866; 13.9 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 9)
      The Benninghoff siblings owned a hotel in Sprague, Washington, which was destroyed in a fire, before moving in 1885 to Billings, Montana, where they built the Grand Hotel
    - Studio portrait of Myron S. Meeks (born 1862), a Northern Pacific Railroad Company agent, North Yakima, Washington, circa 1887-1895; 13.8 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 9)
  - McKay, Rollin H.
    Photographer in Missoula, Montana
    - A Flathead Indian village, 1905; 9.9 x 14.4 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 9)
  - McKenzie, G. W.
    - Man, possibly G. W. McKenzie, standing in front of a tent, circa 1885-1890; 13.8 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 9)
  - McKirahan & Whittier
    Photography studio in Georgetown, Colorado; partnership of Charles A. McKirahan and Jacob Whittier
    - Battleground of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1883; 11.9 x 20.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
    - Boating on Green Lake, Colorado, circa 1883; 12.0 x 20.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
  - McLean, Lachlan, 1843-1929
    Photographer in Idaho Springs, Colorado
    - View looking southwest of Idaho Springs, Colorado, circa 1902; 10.1 x 15.5 cm on mount 10.7 x 16.3 cm (Box 9)
  - McLellan, Charles T. (born 1847)
    McLellan was a division superintendent of the Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad in Lecompton, Kansas
    - Breakwater protection on the banks of the Kansas River in Lecompton, Kansas, circa 1895; 11.9 x 16.9 cm on mount 20.3 x 25.5 cm (Box 9)
  - Mears
    - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Augustine Magloire Alexander Blanchet (1797-1887), Bishop of Walla Walla, Washington, 8.1 x 5.2 cm on mount 10.5 x 6.7 cm (Box 9)
      A biographical sketch of Blanchet on verso and a request to "pray for the repose of [his] soul"
  - Meddaugh, James E. (born 1862)
    Photographer in Rushville, Nebraska; often listed as James S. Meddaugh and J. E. Meddaugh
    - Studio portrait of Big Roads, a Sioux Indian, 1891 Jan 13; 13.9 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 9)
    - Ghost Dance, 1891 Jan 13; 9.3 x 16.3 cm on mount 10.1 x 17.7 cm (Box 9)
      Large group of Indians dancing, photographed from a distance
  - Mellen, George E.
    - Seven Falls, Colorado, height 500 feet, circa 1888; 18.2 x 10.5 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 9)
    - A scene near Manitou Springs, Colorado, circa 1888; 18.6 x 11.8 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.6 cm (Box 9)
      Small bridge over a creek with mountains in the distance
    - Denver and Rio Grande Railroad tracks at Castle Gate, Utah, circa 1888; 11.3 x 18.6 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 9)
    - Denver and Rio Grande Railroad tracks at Castle Gate, Utah, circa 1888; 11.2 x 18.6 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.4 cm (Box 9)
    - Balanced Rock, Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1888; 18.5 x 11.1 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 9)